{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"R.E.M.","incorrectAnswers":["Counting Crows","Three 6 Mafia","The Velvet Underground"],"question":"Which American alternative rock band released the song 'Losing My Religion'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"12 and -12","incorrectAnswers":["144 and -144","24 and -24","12 and 24"],"question":"What are the two different values of the square root of 144?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"3","incorrectAnswers":["1","2","4"],"question":"In the nursery rhyme Baa Baa Black Sheep, how many bags of wool does the sheep have?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Charles Dickens","incorrectAnswers":["Thomas Hardy","George Eliot","Oscar Wilde"],"question":"Who wrote \"A Tale Of Two Cities\"?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Mannerism","incorrectAnswers":["Surrealism","Fauvism","Impressionism"],"question":"Which art movement arose in reaction to the High Renaissance, featuring elongated, contorted poses, crowded canvases, and harsh lighting and coloring?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Austrian","incorrectAnswers":["Czech","Hungarian","German"],"question":"What Nationality Was Mozart?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Prince","incorrectAnswers":["James Brown","Chris Brown","Jamiroquai"],"question":"With Which Artist Is The Funk Band 'The New Power Generation' Associated?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"4","incorrectAnswers":["2","6","16"],"question":"How many times bigger than a regular bottle is a Jeroboam?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Tashkent","incorrectAnswers":["Ulaanbaatar","Yaren District","Tarawa"],"question":"What is the capital city of Uzbekistan?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Chopsticks","incorrectAnswers":["Sticky tape","His fingers","A shotglass"],"question":"What did the Karate Kid use to catch a fly?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Brawn ","incorrectAnswers":["Poald","Swile","Grint"],"question":"By What is the seasoned jellied loaf made from the head of a pig generally known?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Tehran","incorrectAnswers":["Dubai","Istanbul","Tel Aviv"],"question":"Which of these cities is in Iran?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Bob Dylan","incorrectAnswers":["Neil Young","Eric Clapton","Alanis Morissette"],"question":"Which American musician released the album 'Highway 61 Revisited'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"\"We rob banks.\"","incorrectAnswers":["\"You can't handle the truth!\"","\"There's no place like home.\"","\"Carpe diem. Seize the day, boys. Make your lives extraordinary.\""],"question":"Which of these quotes is from the film 'Bonnie and Clyde'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"1990","incorrectAnswers":["1980","1985","1995"],"question":"In which year was Nelson Mandela released from prison?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Dutch ","incorrectAnswers":["German","Danish","French"],"question":"What nationality is the lager producer, `grolsch'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Konrad Adenauer","incorrectAnswers":["Thomas Wergel","Alfred Muller","Karl Barwitz"],"question":"Who was the first chancellor of West Germany after WWII?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Forest Whitaker","incorrectAnswers":["Dan Aykroyd","Christian Bale","Shah Rukh Khan"],"question":"Which actor has featured in films including Rogue One and Black Panther?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Jeff Bridges","incorrectAnswers":["Michael Douglas","Errol Flynn","John Wayne"],"question":"Which actor played the role of The Dude in The Big Lebowski?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Walter Scott","incorrectAnswers":["Oscar Wilde","J. R. R. Tolkien","Alphonse Daudet"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Waverley'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Budapest","incorrectAnswers":["Pécs","Prague","Salzburg"],"question":"What is the capital of Hungary? ","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Sherlock Holmes","incorrectAnswers":["Harry Potter","Charles Dickens","Thomas Hardy"],"question":"Who is associated with the address 221B Baker Street, London?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Seattle Sounders","incorrectAnswers":["Seattle Bengals","Seattle Union","Seattle Flyers"],"question":"Which of these is a soccer team based in Seattle?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Linkin Park","incorrectAnswers":["Alice in Chains","Hollywood Undead","System of a Down"],"question":"Which band was Chester Bennington a member of?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"George Hudson","incorrectAnswers":["Isambard Kingdom Brunel","Robert Stephenson","Thomas Telford"],"question":"In The 19th Century Who Was The Railway King?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Ireland","incorrectAnswers":["Vietnam","Iceland","Israel"],"question":"Which region of the world uses '.ie' at the end of its web addresses?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Humphrey Bogart","incorrectAnswers":["Dennis Hopper","Peter O'Toole","Errol Flynn"],"question":"Which actor played the role of Fred C. Dobbs in The Treasure of the Sierra Madre?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Sandro Botticelli","incorrectAnswers":["Leonardo da Vinci","‎Salvador Dalí","‎Vincent van Gogh"],"question":"Which artist painted \"The Birth of Venus\"","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Hugo Weaving","incorrectAnswers":["Tobey Maguire","Timothy Spall","Elijah Wood"],"question":"Which actor has starred in films including The Lord of the Rings and Captain America: The First Avenger?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Stringed","incorrectAnswers":["Brass","Woodwind","Percussion"],"question":"What type of instrument is a harpsichord?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"San Antonio Spurs","incorrectAnswers":["San Antonio Hawks","San Antonio Brewers","San Antonio Dynamo"],"question":"Which of these is a basketball team based in San Antonio?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"The Danube","incorrectAnswers":["The Nile","The Amazon","The Congo"],"question":"Which river has the most capital cities on it?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"plants; botany","incorrectAnswers":["the study or exploration of caves","the science of preparing and handling microscopic objects for study","wonders, or monsters"],"question":"What is Phytology the study of?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Istanbul","incorrectAnswers":["Ankara","Bursa","Edirne"],"question":"What was the capital of the Ottoman Empire during most of its existence?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"The Song Of Hiawatha","incorrectAnswers":["Beowulf","The Divine Comedy","Paradise Lost"],"question":"What is the name of the 1855 poem that includes sections such as \"The Peace Pipe\", \"The White-Man's Foot\" & \"Blessing The Corn Fields\"?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Indianapolis Colts","incorrectAnswers":["Indianapolis Kings","Indianapolis Ravens","Indianapolis Bucks"],"question":"Which of these is an American Football team based in Indianapolis?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Amelia Earhart","incorrectAnswers":["Bessie Coleman","Jacqueline Cochran","Harriet Quimby"],"question":"Who piloted a plane across the Pacific Ocean from Hawaii to the American mainland in 1935?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Medicine ","incorrectAnswers":["Aphrodisiac","Wedding Gift","Religious Offering"],"question":"For what was licourice used in ancient Egypt?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"13","incorrectAnswers":["1","2","8"],"question":"What is the atomic number of aluminum?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Nuremberg","incorrectAnswers":["Berlin","Munich","Frankfurt"],"question":"In 1945, which German city hosted the trials where former Nazi leaders were prosecuted for war crimes?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"A rogue wins the heart of a rich widow and assumes her dead husband's aristocratic position.","incorrectAnswers":["A naive youth leader is appointed to fill a vacancy in the U.S. Senate.","After a girl is uprooted from her life, her emotions conflict on how best to navigate a new life.","A family heads to a hotel for the winter where a presence influences the father into violence."],"question":"What is the plot of the movie Barry Lyndon?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Ribbon pasta","incorrectAnswers":["Strand pasta","Tubular pasta","Stuffed pasta"],"question":"What type of pasta is tagliatelle?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"South America","incorrectAnswers":["Africa","Central Asia","India"],"question":"From which part of the world do potatoes originate?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Pickling","incorrectAnswers":["Chilling","Canning","Smoking"],"question":"What is the process of soaking and storing food in brine or vinegar?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Quomodocunquizing","incorrectAnswers":["Agastopia","Snickersnee","Jentacular"],"question":"Which word is defined as 'making money in any way that you can'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Onions","incorrectAnswers":["Garlic","Carrots","Broccoli"],"question":"Which vegetable is scientifically named Allium cepa?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Jack London","incorrectAnswers":["Edgar Rice Burroughs","James Fenimore Cooper","Frederik Pohl"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Martin Eden'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"The Wizard of Oz","incorrectAnswers":["Citizen Kane","Network","The Public Enemy"],"question":"Which film contains the character 'Dorothy Gale'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Charles Dickens","incorrectAnswers":["Thomas Hardy","Jane Austen","Edgar Allen Poe"],"question":"Who was the author of 'A Christmas Carol'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"France","incorrectAnswers":["Spain","Portugal","England"],"question":"Which country's troops were defeated by Mexico's army at Puebla in 1862, leading to the celebration of Cinco de Mayo?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A Bull","incorrectAnswers":["A Stallion","A Macho","A Cob"],"question":"What is the word for a male whale?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Ribbon pasta","incorrectAnswers":["Soup pasta","Strand pasta","Tubular pasta"],"question":"What type of pasta is lasagne?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Rome","incorrectAnswers":["Venice","Florence","Milan"],"question":"What is the capital city of Italy?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"India","incorrectAnswers":["China","Russia","Saudi Arabia"],"question":"Where is Kolkata?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Hayley Atwell","incorrectAnswers":["Cobie Smulders","Cate Blanchett","Evangeline Lilly"],"question":"The role of Agent Peggy Carter in the Marvel Cinematic Universe is played by which actor?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"A family heads to a hotel for the winter where a presence influences the father into violence.","incorrectAnswers":["A group of low-level criminals fight to track down a priceless stolen diamond.","After the death of a tycoon, reporters scramble to uncover the meaning of his final utterance.","A car designer and driver battle to build a revolutionary race car."],"question":"What is the plot of the movie The Shining?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Amber","incorrectAnswers":["Myrr","Lapis Lazuli","Tar"],"question":"What is the name of the fossilized resin from prehistoric pine trees that can preserve insects inside of it?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Stamppot","incorrectAnswers":["Ropa Vieja","Meat Pie","Ramen"],"question":"Which of these dishes is most associated with Netherlands?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Africa","incorrectAnswers":["Asia","Autralasia","North America"],"question":"The small red deer is the only type of deer found on which continent? ","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Will Smith","incorrectAnswers":["Brian Cox","Ralph Fiennes","Ryan Reynolds"],"question":"Which actor has appeared in films including Suicide Squad and Enemy of the State?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Neoclassicism","incorrectAnswers":["post-impressionism","Mannerism","Surrealism"],"question":"The painting \"Portrait of Madame Recamier\" by Jacques-Louis David is a part of which art movement?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Mecca","incorrectAnswers":["Jerusalem","Baghdad","Istanbul"],"question":"Which is the holiest city in Islam?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Cambridge","incorrectAnswers":["Oxford","Boston","New York"],"question":"What are the names of two cities, one in England and one in the United States, both of which are famous for their universities?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Moroni","incorrectAnswers":["Ouagadougou","Tegucigalpa","Conakry"],"question":"What is the capital city of Comoros?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Cairo","incorrectAnswers":["Rome","Kyiv","Athens"],"question":"Where was the Rosetta Stone found?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Rolling Stones","incorrectAnswers":["McFly","Delirious?","Depeche Mode"],"question":"Which English rock band released the studio album 'Let It Bleed'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Profit","incorrectAnswers":["Gross Revenue","Income Tax","Share Price"],"question":"What is the term for the amount of money a company makes after accounting for all its costs?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Biggie Smalls","incorrectAnswers":["Dr. Dre","Ice Cube","Tupac Shakur"],"question":"Which rapper had the hit song 'Big Poppa' in the 1990s?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Nigeria","incorrectAnswers":["Afghanistan","Syria","Belarus"],"question":"Which country's flag can be described as 'Three equal vertical bands of green white and green.'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Chicken Machboos","incorrectAnswers":["Ambuyat","Pepperpot","Pho"],"question":"Which of these dishes is most associated with Bahrain?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Queen","incorrectAnswers":["Level 42","Deep Purple","Feeder"],"question":"Which British rock band released the album 'The Miracle'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Jim Carrey","incorrectAnswers":["Gerard Butler","Hugh Jackman","Michael Fassbender"],"question":"Which actor has starred in films including The Mask and The Truman Show?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Naomi Watts","incorrectAnswers":["Melissa Leo","Frances Conroy","Laura Linney"],"question":"Which actress has featured in both Birdman and Twin Peaks?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Tomorrow Never Dies","incorrectAnswers":["Casino Royale","Moonraker","On Her Majesty's Secret Service"],"question":"Which James Bond theme song was performed by Sheryl Crow?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Simon & Garfunkel","incorrectAnswers":["MercyMe","Three 6 Mafia","The Velvet Underground"],"question":"Which American music duo released the album 'Bookends'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Muharram","incorrectAnswers":["Ramadan","Shawwal","Jumada Al-Awwal"],"question":"What is the name of the first month of the year in the Islamic calendar?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Thomas Malthus","incorrectAnswers":["Michelangelo","Gregory Pincus","Alexander Fleming"],"question":"Which influential historical person was  \na scholar who raised concern over growing population?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Queso","incorrectAnswers":["Salsa","Guacamole","Hummus"],"question":"Which of these is a type of Mexican cheese dip?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Africa","incorrectAnswers":["Central Asia","Southeast Asia","North America"],"question":"Where in the world are watermelons originally from?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"James Brown","incorrectAnswers":["Marvin Gaye","Stevie Wonder","Ray Charles"],"question":"Nicknamed the Godfather Of Soul, who died on Christmas Day 2006?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Belarus","incorrectAnswers":["Ireland","Bosnia and Herzegovina","Nigeria"],"question":"Which of these countries has red on its flag?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Rwanda","incorrectAnswers":["Indonesia","South Africa","Brazil"],"question":"Swahili is a language spoken in which of these countries?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Emilio Estevez","incorrectAnswers":["Martin Sheen","Joe Estevez","Christian Slater"],"question":"What is the name of the older brother of Charlie Sheen who made his feature film debut in \"Tex\" at the age of 20?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"North Africa","incorrectAnswers":["Ghana","Belgium","South America"],"question":"Tagine is a dish that is most associated with which part of the world?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Metamorphic Rocks","incorrectAnswers":["Igneous Rocks","Sedimentary Rocks","Fossils"],"question":"What type of rock is formed when existing rocks are subjected to extreme heat and pressure?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Iraq","incorrectAnswers":["Bahrain","Qatar","Iran"],"question":"Which of these countries borders Kuwait?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Rachel Weisz","incorrectAnswers":["Salma Hayek","Catherine Deneuve","Audrey Hepburn"],"question":"Which actress has appeared in both The Bourne Legacy and The Mummy?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Brazil","incorrectAnswers":["France","Italy","West Germany"],"question":"Which country won the 1958 FIFA World Cup, hosted in Sweden?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Audrey Hepburn","incorrectAnswers":["Grace Kelly","Marilyn Monroe","Katharine Hepburn"],"question":"Which famous actress played the titular role in the 1954 film 'Sabrina'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Gorgonzola","incorrectAnswers":["Gouda","Provolone","Mozzarella"],"question":"Which of these cheeses has a blue-green vein?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"U2","incorrectAnswers":["Public Image Ltd.","The Script","The Cure"],"question":"Which Irish rock band released the song 'Beautiful Day'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Barack Obama","incorrectAnswers":["Bill Clinton","George Bush","Donald Trump"],"question":"Which former US president's wife is called Michelle? ","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Founder of Manichaeism, a gnostic religion which for a time was a rival to Christianity.","incorrectAnswers":["Dictator of Nazi Germany.","Founder of the Achaemenid Empire, the first Persian Empire.","Spiritual teacher and central figure of Christianity."],"question":"Which of the following was Mani famous for?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Russia ","incorrectAnswers":["Austria","Switzerland","Norway"],"question":"In Which Country Is Europe's Highest Mountain Mt Elbrus?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Cruella De Vil","incorrectAnswers":["Ursula","Maleficent","Yzma"],"question":"Who wanted to make a coat out of 101 Dalmatians","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A Crash","incorrectAnswers":["A Loom","A Brush","A Forest"],"question":"What Is The Collective Name For Rhinoceroses?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"The Departed","incorrectAnswers":["Babel","Letters from Iwo Jima","Little Miss Sunshine"],"question":"Which film won the Academy Award for Best Picture in 2006?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Roseau","incorrectAnswers":["Georgetown","Nouakchott","Valletta"],"question":"What is the capital city of Dominica?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Sinai","incorrectAnswers":["Jerusalem","Zion","Lebanon"],"question":"On which mountain did Moses receive the Ten Commandments?","difficulty":"medium"},